If my blood work is within good ranges,
but my total test is abnormally high. He
says
1,200,300. Does this mean I should lower
dosage? I feel awesome. More energy,
focus, libido, and so
on. Yeah, we wouldn't want you feeling
that. That's a problem. You know, feel
awesome, more energy, more libido. Nah,
it's that's that's a problem. You need
to go back to feeling like crap. Um, no,
that's that's that's fantastic. Um, so
that level is not abnormally high.
That's assuming that we're talking about
total uh in the typical units used in
the US. Um that's that's that's
fantastic. That's typically the total
level that people need assuming that
your SHBG is about average to receive a
therapeutic free testosterone level. The
problem with the reference range is that
the reference range has been driven down
into the gutter and it it it drops so
rapidly in real time. Like in in
Australia when I started doing this
primarily which was in 2019 the
reference range was about and we use
different units was 10 to 33 or 10 to
35. Now it's 5 to 25. Like that's a
humongous drop. Um and that's just been
in the recent like six years. So this if
you actually go on to PubMed, the total
testosterone reference range for men of
all ages. So we're talking, you know,
teenagers to to um geriatric elderly men
goes up to the high 1200s. So I mean the
reference range at the moment is
absurdly low, but no, this is this is
not abnormally high. This is a
therapeutic response to treatment. This
is a healthy testosterone level for a
healthy man, and that's why you feel
good. So, uh, no, that that's the goal
that you're feeling good. Keep it up.
Don't worry about it. And, um, yeah,
that's a positive.